Finding aid for the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive Collection of Audio Materials, 1970-1999 LSC.2230
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Various Topics Cassettes, 1976-1994; Series 12.; 40 audio cassette tapes
  - Yer Girlfriend, L-Word Spoken Here, 1991; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 2)
    Professionally recorded music album of group, Yer Girlfriend. Album title is "L-Word Spoken Here." Group includes Carol Kraemer, Laura Shine, Kathy Weisbach, Patty O. Veranda, and Phyllis Free. album was produced by Yer Girlfirend and Rog Magallon, was recorded at Studio 2002 in New Albany, Indiana, and was distributed by Esther Records. Songs on Side A: Take Another Step, Painfully True, PMS Breakdown, Take Back Our Lives and L-Word. Songs on Side B: Dyketime, Torn, Still Waters, Angry Atthis, and Remain. Liner notes include song lyrics and images of band members.
  - Christianity and Tolerance, 22 October 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 3)
    John Boswell discusses his book, Christianity, Social Tolerance, and Homosexuality (published 1980). Boswell reads excerpts from the book and argues that homosexuality was not necessarily condemned in the ancient and medieval world. He questions whether the Bible is really a foundation for the negative attitudes and hostility toward homosexuality that are present in the modern world.
  - Why Dykes Go Straight Forum, 24 October 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 4)
    Recording of forum, "Why Dykes Go Straight," where various issues surrounding being a lesbian are discussed, including family relationships, work environment, support systems available, coming out, and keeping homosexuality a secret.
  - National Lesbian Conference: Future Workshop, Tape 2 of 2, 10 October 1988; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 5)
    Recording of panel at the National Lesbian Conference, organized by the National Organization for Women, in San Diego, CA. Belinda Paras and Michelle Crone are speakers. Politics, elections, legislation, coalitions, and social change are discussed.
    Tape 1 in Conference Cassettes series, Box 2, Folder 7.
  - TV and Children, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 6)
    Tape is ripped and unplayable.
  - Helen in Egypt, 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 7)
    A reading of the epic poem, Helen in Egypt, written by H.D.(born Hilda Doolittle). In the poem, Helen of Troy is given a voice to share her story. From the audio cassette's liner notes: "This recording was made some time between September and November 1955 in Switzerland."
  - Bev Kozlow Interview, 1 May 1984; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 8)
    Recording of interview with Bev Kozlow. She discusses her education, personal life, writing, entry into and relationship with the US Army, and her experience working with various organizations and groups.
  - Women and the Arts - UWEX, 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 9)
    Recording of University of Wisconsin-Extension (UWEX) Conference panel with speaker, Maryo G. Ewell, the Director of Community Art Program in Colorado. Ewell shares the activities that are being done at her program and explains the feminist definition of community arts.
  - Connexxus Intern Training: Drugs, 6 June 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 10)
    Informative training session on drugs, addiction, and treatment. Cover alcohol, LSD, PCP, other hallucinogens, narcotics, etc. Speaker is Maria Acosta.
  - A Visit with Two First-Century Women Who Loved Women / Post-Christian Feminist Spirituality, 30 November 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 11)
    Recording of academic talks organized and presented by the Lazarus Project. Dr. Bernadette Brooten presents "A Visit with Two First-Century Women Who Loved Women," with research on lesbians in antiquity. Dr. Brooten is a religious scholar, focused on the New Testament, Judaism, early literature and history, women and religion, and feminist sexual ethics. Dr. Ann Matter presents "Post-Christian Feminist Spirituality," detailing worship, God, the goddess and spirituality. Dr. Matter's areas of expertise are history of Christian culture, history of interpretation of the Bible, spirituality and mysticism in the Christian tradition, women in Christian history, and sexuality in Christian history.
  - Meet the Peace and Freedom Party / Socialist Feminist Slate, Tape 1 of 2, 19 May 1990; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 12-13)
    90 minute recording of talk about the purpose, values, and goals of the Peace and Freedom party and the upcoming elections in California. Party candidates introduce themselves, share platform for election of desired position, and respond to questions from audience. Held at the State Building in Los Angeles, CA.
  - Buffalo Women's Oral History / Paris Lesbians in 1920s, 9-10 October 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 14)
    Recording of talks at the Gay Academic Union National Conference in Chicago on October 9 and 10, 1982. Side 1 is a recording of "Buffalo Women's Oral History Project," with speakers Liz Kennedy and Madeline Davis, on Oct 10, 1982. "Buffalo Women's Oral History Project" is a description of a study conducted of the lesbian community in Buffalo, NY in 1940-1960s. Side 2 is "Paris Lesbians in 1920s," with speaker Karla Jay, on October 9, 1982. "Paris Lesbians" shares an account of notable lesbians in Paris in the 1920s.
    Recording is taken from audience, so speaker's voice is at a distance.
  - Coming Out Stories, Spring 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 15)
    Recording of personal coming out stories told by women in Pamela Grey's Lesbian Lives class at San Francisco State University in spring 1983.
    Handwritten label on tape indicated, "Tape 1 of 2 Tapes." Second tape is not in box.
  - Ralph MacCowan, On Coming Out, 1 March 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 16)
    Interview with Ralph MacCowan, describing her personal coming out story. Also discuss relationships with women, family environment, and work.
    Handwritten label on tape indicates, Tape 2, but no other related tapes are in box.
  - Breast Cancer Update, 11 November 1994; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 17)
    Dr. Susan Love presents research and conclusions about breast cancer as of 1994. Covers various issues and myths surrounding breast cancer, including risk factors, sexual orientation as risk factor, testing, lack of prevention, treatment, and health care.
  - Fat Sisters, Translation of Sappho, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 18)
    Reading of Mary Barnard's translation of Sappho. Reader may be Elana Dykewomon. Sappho was an Ancient Greek poet from the island of Lesbos. Her poetry focused on physical relationships and passion, with both men and women, contributing to the foundation of the term, lesbians.
  - Alice Block Interview for Lesbian News Issues, December 1985-January 1986; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 5, Item 19)
    Alice Block is interviewed by Claudia J. McMullen for Lesbian News Issues. Discuss her career as a writer, family, involvement with Judaism, time spent in Israel, personal experience as lesbian, and writing on the topic of lesbianism.
  - KPFK: Time Line, 1984; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 1)
    Recording of KPFK 90.7 FM radio presentation, Time Line, which was put together with clips for the radio show, IMRU. Time Line was a review key events and movements in gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transsexual history. The episode focused on events from the late 1960s and the 1970s, such as the Stonewall Riots in 1969, Anita Bryant's 1977 reaction to a Dade County's ordinance prohibiting discrimination based on sexuality, Harvey Milk's swearing in as a San Francisco Supervisor in January 1978, his assassination in November of that year, and more protests and marches. IMRU is a weekly live progressive radio magazine covering news, entertainment, culture, social justice & issues of interest to the LGBT community of Southern California.
  - Karlene Earina / Norma Stafford, April 1997; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 2)
    Meeting or discussion with Karlene Earina and Norma Stafford. A variety of speakers, perhaps from audience, discuss political affiliation, feminism, and lesbian issues. Norma Stafford was an American poet who began writing while she was an inmate at the California Institution for Women.
    Recording was taken from audience, speaker is almost unintelligible.
  - Lesbian Pulp, 21 April 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 3)
    Birdie Yusba presents talk on lesbian literary history, focusing on lesbian paperback pulp fiction. Yusba outlines the history of lesbian pulp, explains its cultural and historical significance, discusses various authors' experience with writing and readers, and shares examples of specific nobles with analysis.
  - Battering in Relationships, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 4)
    Side 1 of tape begins with advertisement for adoption of orphan children. Majority of recording is a KPFA radio show, Women's Magazine, with host, Reyna Lee and guests, Del Martin and Susan Elizabeth. Show's topic is domestic violence (emotional and physical), with callers sharing their personal experiences with domestic violence and a discussion on domestic violence in homosexual relationships, the effects experienced by victims and resources available. Del Martin was a San Francisco reporter, writer, feminist, and gay-rights activist. Side 2 is interview with Harriet Davis, who was in a relationship with a man who was physically and verbally abusive and is accused of killing him.
    Tape label indicates that this is Tape 2 of 2, but Tape 1 is not in collection box.
  - Pat Denslow, October 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 5)
    Conversation with Pat Denslow about her ideas on religion, literature, feminism, lesbianism, and the dynamics within feminist and lesbian groups.
  - Karlene Faith and R. Ruth Linden: Prisons, 29 November 1976; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 6)
    Karlene Faith and Robin Ruth Linden discuss women in prisons. The talk took place in Los Angeles, CA. Faith is a feminist and human rights activist, and has also written books on the topic of women and incarceration (Unruly Women: The Politics of Confinement and Resistance, 1993). Linden is a sociologist that specializes in feminism, women's health, and techno-medicine. Side 2 of tape is predominantly a recording of music.
    One of the speakers is hard to understand.
  - Panel on Lesbian Sexuality: Older Women, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 7)
    Panel moderated by [Hill?] Bender, a student at the Institute for Advanced Study of Human Sexuality in San Francisco, CA, focused on studying lesbians and issues with age and sexuality. Speakers on the panel discuss various issues that arise in sexuality with age, and also take questions from the audience. Matilde Moore is a panelist, a doctor who holds therapy groups for older women, who discusses frequent issues she has encountered in her practice.
  - Lesbians Consider Parenting, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 8)
    Panel on the topic of lesbians parenting, covering the various issues that women confront when considering and beginning to parent. Panelists take questions from audience and discuss topics such as insemination, sperm donors, choosing the biological parent, health care, single parenthood, family relationships, economic issues, parenting counseling, and how lesbians parenting are viewed by the public.
  - Women of Antiquity, [ca. 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 9)
    Leslie Calman, professor of women's studies and political science at Barnard College, outlines the development of the contemporary feminist movement in the United States. Calman makes clear that there are several movements, that have different roots and varying organization and ideologies. Calman also discusses the different types of women who joined the feminist movement throughout the 20th century. In Side 2, Calman reads from texts from her course, Women in Antiquity, focusing on documented stories of women-common and powerful women-in antiquity. She notes the lack of women in politics and the intellectual sphere.
  - Current Themes in Women's Writing: Masturbation, 1974; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 10)
    From the program, Current Themes, the episode is titled Masturbation and is recorded in Los Angeles, CA. The goal of the program is to familiarize women with "loving themselves" in order to free themselves. Included are personal accounts of women first becoming familiar with masturbation, poetry readings, and excerpts from novels.
  - Telewoman Newsletter: Olis Restaurant, [ca. early 1980s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 11)
    Interview with Barbara and Jean of Oli's Restaurant in San Francisco, CA, by Telewoman Newsletter. Discuss details about the restaurant's hours, type of food, and clientele, as well as the concept of a completely woman-run restaurant. Telewoman was a San Francisco Bay Area newsletter, published from 1980 to 1983.
  - Ann Bradley's Lesbian Writers Series: Willyce Kim and Kitty Tsui, 18 March 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 12)
    From Ann Bradley's Lesbian Writers Series. Recording was taken at Different Light Book Store, a book store dedicated to gay and lesbian literature and news. Side 1 is Willyce Kim reading passages from her novel, Dead Heat (published in 1988), and poetry from a recently completed manuscript. Kitty Tsui also reads from a recently completed manuscript. Kitty Tsui was born in Hong Kong, raised in California, and is a poet, activist, and body builder.
  - Ageism and Medical Care for Old Lesbians, 10 July 1992; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 13)
    Recorded at the 14th annual National Lesbian and Gay Health Conference, a panel on medical care for older lesbians. Speakers from Old Lesbians Organizing for Change coalition, discuss issues arising in older lesbian communities, including family, retirement, health care, age, and sexuality.
  - Liz Kennedy at UCLA, 16 February 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 14)
    Dr. Elizabeth Lapovsky Kennedy presents her research, compiled from oral histories, on lesbian women from the 1930s to 1960s at UCLA. Recording begins Karen Sax giving opening remarks to the series, Reclaiming Honor and Rejoicing in Lesbian Herstory, co-sponsored by the Center for the Study of Women at UCLA. Liz Kennedy and Marge Kramer follow with lectures on their research in the field of women's studies. Dr. Kennedy (born 1939) pioneered the foundation for the field of Women's Studies and is a gay and lesbian historian whose book Boots of Leather, Slippers of Gold: A History of the Lesbian Community (co-authored with Madeline Davis and published in 1993) documents the lesbian community of Buffalo, NY in the decades before Stonewall.
  - Cheryl Clark: Living as a Lesbian, 30 March 1989; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 15)
    Cheryl Clarke reading from her novel, Living as a Lesbian (published in 1986), at Cal State University Los Angeles. Clarke reads from her book of poetry, Narratives: Poems in the Tradition of Black Women (1982), and another book, Humid Pitch (1989). Clarke is a Black feminist writer, activist, and professor from Washington DC.
  - Casselberry-Dupree, [ca. 1990s]; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 16)
    Recording of music duo, Casselberry-Dupree. Music incorporates African, Latin, and reggae influence with folk, soul, and country.
    Audio on Side 1 only. Audio cassette tape and case both have the note, Do Not Copy.
  - Saunders and Goldberg, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 17)
    First, explanation and discussion over survey research results about gay and lesbian community in Los Angeles. Followed by presentation of research survey, Nationwide Survey of Lesbians Over 65.
  - Madness, undated; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 18)
    Discussion on women who are incarcerated and/or placed in mental health institutions. Also discuss depression, shock treatment, and involuntary/voluntary psychiatry.
    Side 1 only
  - KHSU Women's Show: Older Lesbians, 1 September 1987; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 19)
    Recording of Humboldt State University's (Arcata, CA) KHSU radio show, "Women's Show: Lesbian Concentrate." Focus of episode is interviews with older lesbians and discussing the topic of ageism in the lesbian community.
  - Mary, Myth, and Mysticism: The Past Transformation into the Future, 30 November 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 3, Folder 6, Item 20)
    As part of The Lazarus Project, Dr. Ann Matter presents a talk on Christian feminism and the possibility that Christianity, spirituality, and the goddess in history are all connected to present-day issues having to do with lesbians and religion. Dr. Matter (born 1947) is Associate Dean for Arts & Letters and Professor of Religious Studies at the University of Pennsylvania. She specializes in Medieval Christianity, including mysticism, women and religion, sexuality and religion, manuscript and textual studies and sacred music.
- Conference Cassettes, 1972-1999; Series 11.; 34 audio cassette tapes
  Recordings of various festivals and conferences of different topics, including minority issues, feminism, rape, lesbian topics, health, ageism, etc.
  - Conferences/Festivals Yosemite Debates/Pacific Center Resolutions, 25 October 1981; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 1-2)
    Recording of meetings, debates and resolutions over planning of and issues surrounding conferences and festivals that are focused on women. Topics included in the recording: women of color, Jewish women, Robin Tyler, racism, classism, anti-Semitism, working class women, money, and substance use.
  - Gay Olympic Games Interviews, August 1982; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 3)
    Interviews with participating athletes in Gay Olympic Games, first held in San Francisco in 1982. Interviewees were mainly women, and discussed personal background, training, fundraising, camaraderie at Games, and experience participating as "out" lesbians.
  - National Association for Lesbian and Gay Gerontology Conference on Aging: Sexuality Panel, 25 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 4)
    Recording of panel on sexuality at NALGG Conference on Aging. Women discuss personal relationships, sexual activity, agism, and other issues related to sexuality.
  - National Association for Lesbian and Gay Gerontology Conference on Aging: Oral Histories, 25 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 5-6)
    Panel on conducting and the importance of oral histories for gay and lesbians at NALGG Conference on Aging.
  - National Association for Lesbian and Gay Gerontology Conference on Aging: Rural Lesbian Panel, 25 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 7)
    Panel discussion about lesbians in rural areas. Topics include personal experiences growing up in rural areas, living in rural areas as adults, and the kind of work participating lesbians from rural areas are doing-specifically, working with senior community.
  - National Association for Lesbian and Gay Gerontology Conference on Aging: Illness in the Lesbian Community, 25 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 8)
    Forum based on the topics of catastrophic and chronic illnesses in women-specifically lesbian women-encounter in older age and the ways in which persons have coped and dealt with illnesses. Also discuss emotional and physical stress, family relationships, personal relationships, health care system, and medical costs.
  - National Association for Lesbian and Gay Gerontology Conference on Aging: Minority Issues, 25 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 9)
    Workshop on the issue of elderly minorities who are gay and lesbian. Moderator uses the term "third world" elderly gay and lesbian. There are four speakers who present their research and experience working with elderly minorities who are gay and lesbian.
  - National Association for Lesbian and Gay Gerontology Conference on Aging: Alternative Housing, 25 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 10)
    Panel at the NALGG Conference on Aging on alternative housing for older gays and lesbians. Discuss instances of group living communities for older men and women, struggles with money, and sexuality.
  - National Association for Lesbian and Gay Gerontology Conference on Aging: Lesbians Over 65 Survey, 30 June 1983; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 11)
    Study conducted by Dr. Monika Kehoe, Sheryl Goldberg, Brenda Spinner.
    Audio is fuzzy, cuts out, and it is hard to understand what speakers say.
  - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force 12th Annual Creating Change Conference: Our Movement's 2nd Century, Tape 1 of 2, 1999; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 12-13)
    Recording of plenary sessions and welcome to participants at The National Gay and Lesbian Task Force's Creating Change Conference in Oakland, California. Announce and celebrate achievements made nationally by national partners. A variety of speakers also discuss own work and achievements.
  - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force 12th Annual Creating Change Conference: Politics is a Many Gendered Thing, Tape 1 of 2, 1999; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 14-15)
    California Governor and Oakland Mayor (at the time) Jerry Brown speaks at National Gay and Lesbian Task Force's 12th Annual Creating Change Conference in Oakland, California. Discusses the activism needs in Oakland, new political and civil initiatives, diversity, and welcomes the conference members to Oakland. Yosenio V. Lewis and Jonathan Winters, as organizers, also welcome conference members to Oakland. San Francisco Supervisor Mark Leno also speaks out against the Knight Initiative/California proposition 22. Plenary panel titled, Politics is a Many Gendered Thing, discusses gender identity, sexual identity, and sexual expression in politics.
  - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force 10th Annual Creating Change Conference: Countering the Radical Right in Communities of Color, 1997; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 16)
    10th Annual Creating Change Conference was held in San Diego. Discussion concerning communities of color, institutionalized racism, and how members of communities can handle racism and discrimination. How to address issue of racial reconciliation.
    Audio is low, hard to understand speaker.
  - 7th Annual National Women's Studies Association Convention: Opening Session, A Celebration of Women, June 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 17)
    Recording of first plenary session at the 7th Annual National Women's Studies Association Convention at the University of Washington in Seattle, Washington. The Convention took place June 18 through June 23 in 1985. The NWSA is based at the University of Maryland. The theme of the convention was "Creating Choices Through Feminist Education"
  - 7th Annual National Women's Studies Association Convention: Common Causes, Uncommon Coalitions, 22 June 1985; audio cassette tape (Box 4, Folder 1, Item 18)
    Recording of third plenary session, Common Causes: Uncommon Coalitions. Presented by the Outreach Committee of the NWSA. Betty Lou Valentine, from the University of Washington, was moderator and introduced the session. Barbara Smith, Charlotte Bunche, Barbara MacDonald, and Merle Woo are the panelist speakers. Each panelist shares perspective on achieving social change in women's issues. Coalitions between academics, lesbians, non-lesbians, feminists, and/or the public are the proposed solutions.